http://www.parsons.com/website-privacy-policy/

Website Privacy Policy
Parsons Corporation understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used and shared online. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits our website www.parsons.com (the “Website”). In this policy, we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information, including personal information, that we obtain about visitors to our Website.
The information we collect through the Website is controlled by Parsons Corporation, which is headquartered in the United States at 5875 Trinity Parkway, Centreville, Virginia, USA.
Information We Collect On The Website
Parsons collects personal information from you when you establish an account with us or when you communicate with us through our Website.
Parsons collects information from Website users automatically through the use of cookies or other similar tracking technologies. Cookies are small bits of information that the website places on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies remember information about your activities on the website to make your visits to the website more enjoyable and valuable to you by providing a customized experience and recognizing your preferences when you return to the website. If you have chosen to disable cookies on your browser, some of the functionality of the Website may be lost. Certain web pages or services provided by Parsons require that cookies be enabled in your browser and cannot be used if cookies are disabled. The information collected through cookies includes Internet addresses, types of operating systems, IP addresses, and browser software and pages accessed by users. For additional information, please see our Cookie Policy.
As part of our recruitment process, Parsons collects and processes personal data relating to job applicants. Parsons is committed to being transparent about how it collects and uses that data, and to meeting its data protection obligations under all applicable laws and regulations. Information that Parsons may collect from you as part of the recruitment process includes:
your name, address, and contact details, including email address and telephone number;
your resume and work history, including details of your qualifications, skills, and experience;
certain financial information, including your current level of compensation, including any benefits;
information about your training, education, certifications, and licenses;
information about your right to work in a specific country, including your passport, work permit, visas, drivers license, date of birth, and social security number;
the outcome of criminal background checks, reference checks, drug tests, and security clearances for certain positions;
information about your race, gender, national or ethnic origin, sexual orientation, religion, or veteran status;
a record of our communications with you via email, telephone, and through our recruiting portal; and
medical information, in certain cases where permitted by law.
Parsons may collect this information through job application forms, resumes or CVs, your passport or other identity documents, or through interviews or other forms of assessment.
We may also collect personal data about you from third parties, such as references supplied by former employers. We may contact third parties and references before making a formal offer to you.
Your recruitment data will be stored in several different places, including on your employment application, in our People Record Center and People systems, and on other IT systems (including email).
Use Of Your Information
Parsons uses your personal information to respond to requests made while you visit our Website. Additionally, Parsons may use your personal information to:
Help diagnose problems with the website and to enhance the Website for an optimal user experience;
Monitor the usage and performance of the website and research aggregate information about users to determine the marketing and advertising efforts of Parsons, its trusted affiliates, independent contractors, and business partners; and
Provide maintenance, support, and customer service for the website.
Process information you provide as part of our recruitment process:
We need to collect, process, and retain data about you to evaluate your qualifications and suitability for employment, and, if selected, extend an offer of employment to you. We may also use your information to keep you informed of new opportunities as they arise.
In some cases, we need to process data to ensure that a successful applicant is eligible to work in a specific country before employment begins. We may also need to process your data to complete relevant security and criminal background checks, as permitted by law, and to respond to and defend against legal claims.
Parsons may process special categories of data, such as information about race, gender, national or ethnic origin, sexual orientation, religion, or veteran status, to monitor and report recruitment statistics. We may also collect medical information to make reasonable accommodations for candidates who have a disability. We process such information to carry out our legal obligations as an employer.
If your application is unsuccessful, Parsons may keep your personal data on file for future employment opportunities for which you may be suited. We will ask for your consent before we retain your data for this purpose, and you are free to withdraw your consent at any time.
You are under no statutory or contractual obligation to provide data to Parsons during the recruitment process. However, if you do not provide the information, we may not be able to process your application properly, or at all.
Sharing Your Information
The personal information you provide to Parsons will be shared, consistent with applicable law, as follows:
With affiliates and subsidiaries of Parsons;
With third parties and third-party business providers that provide services to Parsons, such as companies that provide services for employee recruitment;
With a third party in the event of a sale, merger, reorganization, or other transaction involving part or all of Parsons;
With law enforcement agencies to detect or prevent unlawful activities, and/or to aid in an ongoing investigation;
As required by law or court order;
As needed to support our recruitment process:
Your information may be shared internally with members of the Talent Management and recruitment team, legal advisors, interviewers involved in the recruitment process, managers in the business area with a vacancy, and IT staff, if access to the data is necessary for the performance of their roles.
Parsons uses certain software platforms to collect, retain, and manage data collected from applicants and employees. The providers of that software, including Oracle and Work Day, may have access to your information.
We may also share your information with certain trusted third parties, including taxing authorities, background check and drug testing providers, benefit plan providers, and legal advisors, as required or permitted by law.
Protection Of Your Data
Parsons takes the protection of your personal data seriously. Although there is no such thing as “perfect security” on the Internet, Parsons maintains reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to help protect personal information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.
Retention Of Your Data
Parsons retains your personal data only as long as it is needed for business purposes in accordance with legal, regulatory, and contractual requirements and in accordance with Parsons records retention schedules.
Parsons retains data you provide for recruitment as follows:
If your application for employment is unsuccessful, Parsons will hold your data on file for 3 (three) years after the end of the relevant recruitment process. If you agree to allow us to keep your personal data on file, we will hold your data on file for a further 3 (three) years for consideration for future employment opportunities. At the end of that period, your data is deleted or destroyed. You will be asked for this consent when you submit your CV for consideration.
If your application for employment is successful, personal data gathered during the recruitment process will be transferred to your employee file (electronic and paper-based) and retained by Talent Management during your employment. The periods for which your data will be held will be provided to you in a new privacy notice.
Cross-Border Transfer Of Information
Parsons generally maintains servers and systems in the United States hosted by third-party service providers. We also may subcontract the processing of your data to, or otherwise share your data with, other third parties in the United States or countries other than your country of residence. As a result, where the personal information that we collect through or in connection with the Website is transferred to and processed in the United States or anywhere else outside the European Economic Area (EEA) for the purposes described above, we will take steps to ensure that the information receives the same level of protection as if it remained within the EEA, including entering into data transfer agreements, using the EU Commission approved Standard Contractual Clauses, and by any other means required or suggested by the GDPR.
Additional Notice for EU Persons:
The Legal Bases For Using Your Personal Information
We collect, use, and share your personal information where we are satisfied that we have an appropriate legal basis to do this. This may be because:
Our use of your personal information is in our legitimate interest as a commercial organization (for example in order to make improvements to our products and services and to provide you with information you request); you have a right to object to processing as explained in the section below titled Your legal rights;
Our use of your personal information is necessary to perform a contract or take steps to enter into a contract with you (for example where we use your name and contact information to make travel reservations in the performance of our services); and/or
Our use of your personal information is necessary to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation that we have (for example, where we are required to undertake vetting to comply with safety and security regulations or where we are required to disclose personal information to a court or tax authority).
If you would like to find out more about the legal bases on which we process personal information, please contact us using the details below.
Your Legal Rights
Subject to certain exemptions, and in some cases dependent upon the processing activity we are undertaking, you have certain rights in relation to your personal information:
Right to access, correct, and delete your personal information: You have the right to request access to the personal information that we hold about you and:(a) the source of your personal information; (b) the purposes, legal basis, and methods of processing; (c) the data controller’s identity; and (d) the entities or categories of entities to whom your personal information may be transferred.
You also have the right to request that we delete your information.
We are not required to comply with your request to erase personal information if the processing of your personal information is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation or for the establishment, exercise, or deference of legal claims.
Right to restrict the processing of your personal information: You have the right to restrict the use of your personal information when (i) you contest the accuracy of the data; (ii) the use is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the data; (iii) we no longer need the personal information for the relevant purposes, but we require it for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims; or (iv) you have objected to our personal information use justified on our legitimate interests verification as to whether we have a compelling interest to continue to use your data.
We can continue to use your personal information following a request for restriction, where:
we have your consent; or
to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or
to protect the rights of another natural or legal person.
Right to data portability: To the extent that we process your information (i) based on your consent or under a contract; and (ii) through automated means, you have the right to receive such personal information in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format, or you can ask to have it transferred directly to another data controller.
Right to object to the processing of your personal information: You can object to any processing of your personal information which has our legitimate interests as its legal basis if you believe your fundamental rights and freedoms outweigh our legitimate interests. If you raise an objection, we have an opportunity to demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate interests which override that objection.
Right to obtain a copy of personal information safeguards used for transfers outside your jurisdiction: You can ask to obtain a copy of, or reference to, the safeguards under which your personal information is transferred..
Right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority: You have a right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority if you have concerns about how we are processing your personal information.
We ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us first, although you have a right to contact your supervisory authority at any time.
How to Exercise Your Rights: If you would like to exercise any of the rights described above, please send a request to Parsons’ Information Governance Team at InfoGovernance@parsons.com. In your message, please indicate the right you would like to exercise and the information that you would like to access, review, correct, or delete.
We may ask you for additional information to confirm your identity and for security purposes, before disclosing the personal information requested to you. We reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive.
We may not always be able to fully address your request, for example if it would impact the duty of confidentiality we owe to others, or if we are legally entitled to deal with the request in a different way.
Additional Notice for California Residents:
This California Consumer Privacy Act Notice to California Residents supplements the information contained in our Privacy policies, procedures, and standards, and applies solely to employees, visitors, and other individuals who reside in the State of California (“consumers” or “you”).  We adopt this notice to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”) and other California privacy laws.  Any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this notice.
Information We Collect
We collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or device (“personal information”).  In particular, we have collected the following categories of personal information on consumers as defined under the CCPA within the last twelve (12) months:
Category
Examples
Collected
A. Identifiers
A real name, IP address, email address, or other similar identifiers.
YES
B. Personal Information Categories listed in the California Customer Records Statute (Cal. Civ. Code §1798.80(e))
A name, signature, Social Security Number, address, telephone number, passport number, driver’s license number, insurance policy number, education, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, financial information, medical information, or health insurance information.
YES
C. Protected classification characteristics under California or Federal law.
Age, race, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, pregnancy, childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information.
YES
D. Commercial information
Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies.
NO
E. Biometric Information
Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retina scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data.
NO
F. Internet or similar network activity.
Browsing history, search history, information on interaction with a website, application, or advertisement.
NO
G. Geolocation Data
Physical location or movements.
NO
H. Sensory Data
Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information.
NO
I. Professional or employment-related information.
Current or past job history or performance evaluations.
YES
J. Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g; 34 CFR Part 99).
Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational intuition or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records.
NO
Personal information does not include:
Publicly available information from government records.
De-identified or aggregated consumer information.
Information excluded from the CCPA’s scope, like:
Health or medical information covered by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPPA) and the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act (CMIA) or clinical trial data;
Personal information covered by certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FRCA), the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) or California Financial Information Privacy Act (FIPA) and the Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994.
We obtain the categories of personal information listed above from the following categories of sources:
Directly from you. For example, from forms you complete on our website or job application portal.
Indirectly from you. For example, from observing your actions on our website or job application portal.
Use Of Personal Information
We may use or disclose the personal information we collect for one or more of the following business purposes:
To fulfill or meet the reason you provided the information. For example, if you share your name, contact information, and resume to be considered for a job posting, we will use that personal information in evaluating your qualifications for that position.
To provide you with support and respond to your inquiries, including to investigate your concerns and monitor and improve our responses.
To respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, or government regulations.
As described to you when collecting your personal information or as otherwise set forth in the CCPA.
We will not collect additional categories of personal information or use the personal information we collected for materially different, unrelated, or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.
Sharing Personal Information
We may disclose your personal information to a third party for a business purpose. When we disclose personal information for a business purpose, we enter a contract that describes the purpose and requires the recipient to both keep that personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose except performing the contract.
In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have disclosed the following categories (corresponding with the table above) of personal information for a business purpose: Category A, Category B, Category C, Category I.
We share your personal information with the following categories of third parties: our clients, our service providers, and third parties to whom you or your agents authorize us to disclose your personal information in connection with services we provide to you.
In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have not sold any personal information.
Your Rights And Choices
The CCPA provides California residents with specific rights regarding their personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and explains how to exercise those rights.
Access to Specific Information and Data Portability Rights
You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past twelve (12) months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable request, we will disclose to you:
The categories of personal information we collected about you.
The categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you.
Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or sharing that personal information.
The categories of third parties with whom we share that personal information.
The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).
If we shared your personal information for a business purpose, a list of those disclosures, identifying the personal information categories that each category of recipient obtained.
Deletion Request Rights
You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable request, we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our records, unless an exception applies.
We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service provider(s) to:
Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our contract with you.
Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 et. seq.).
Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information’s deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research’s achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.
Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
Comply with a legal obligation.
Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.
Exercising Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights
To exercise the access, data portability, and deletion rights described above, please submit a verifiable request to us by sending a message to InfoGovernance@parsons.com  Only you, or a person registered with the California Secretary of State that you authorize to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable request related to your personal information. You may also make a verifiable request on behalf of your minor child.
You may only make a verifiable request for access or data portability twice within a 12-month period. The verifiable request must:
Provide enough information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative.
Describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.
We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you. We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable request to confirm the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.
Response Timing and Format
We endeavor to respond to a verifiable r request within forty-five (45) days of its receipt. If we require more time, we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing. We will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option. Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding the verifiable request’s receipt. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily useable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance, specifically by electronic mail communication.
We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.
Personal Information Sales Opt-Out and Opt-In Rights
Parsons does not sell your personal information.
Non-Discrimination
We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. Unless permitted by the CCPA, we will not:
Deny you services.
Provide you a different level of service.
California’s “Shine the Light” law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits employees that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send us an electronic message via InfoGovernance@parsons.com.
Changes To Notice
Parsons may make changes to this Notice. Notification of changes will be posted on this page. You should review this Notice periodically to keep up to date on our most current policies and practices.
Questions And Contact Information
If you have questions regarding this Notice, please contact Parsons’ Information Governance Team at InfoGovernance@parsons.com.
